Guide to the CONSOL Energy, Inc. Mine Maps and Records, 1857-2010 AIS.1991.16
ULS Archives & Special Collections
- Records, 1857-2008; XVIII.
  - Monongahela River Consolidated Coal and Coke Company
    - Surface properties in relation to coal mines, 1.
      - Cincinnati Mine (Box 232A, Folder 17)
      - Clipper Mine (Box 232A, Folder 18)
      - Coal Bluff Mine (Box 232A, Folder 19)
      - Coal Valley Mine (Box 232A, Folder 20)
      - Crescent Mine (Box 232A, Folder 21)
      - Crowthers Mine (Box 232A, Folder 22)
      - Eclipse Mine (Box 232A, Folder 23)
      - Elizabeth Mine, Sheet 1 (Box 232B, Folder 1)
      - Elizabeth Mine, Sheet 2 (Box 232B, Folder 2)
      - Elizabeth Mine, Sheet 3 (Box 232B, Folder 3)
      - Elizabeth Mine, Sheet 4 (Box 232B, Folder 4)
      - Fayette City Mine (Box 232B, Folder 5)
      - Fox Mine, 1908 (Box 232B, Folder 6)
      - Fox Mine, 1909 (Box 232B, Folder 7)
      - Gallatin Mine (Box 232B, Folder 8)
      - Gospel Mine (Box 232B, Folder 9)
      - Guffey Mine, 1908 (Box 232B, Folder 10)
      - Guffey Mine, 1909 (Box 232B, Folder 11)
      - W. S. B. Hayes Mine (Box 232B, Folder 12)
      - Hilldale Mine (Box 232B, Folder 13)
      - Holmes Mine (Box 232B, Folder 14)
      - Ivill Mine, 1908 (Box 232B, Folder 15)
      - Ivill Mine, 1909 (Box 232B, Folder 16)
      - Knob Mine (Box 232B, Folder 17)
      - Little Redstone Mine (Box 232B, Folder 18)
      - Lovedale Mine, Sheet 1, 1908 (Box 232B, Folder 19)
      - Lovedale Mine, Sheet 2, 1908 (Box 232B, Folder 20)
      - Lovedale Mine, Sheet 1, unknown (Box 232B, Folder 21)
      - Lovedale Mine, Sheet 2, unknown (Box 232B, Folder 22)
      - Maple Creek Mine (Box 232B, Folder 23)
      - Mongah and Old Eagle Mines (Box 232B, Folder 24)
      - Mingo Mine (Box 232B, Folder 25)
      - Moorhead Mine (Box 232B, Folder 26)
      - New Eagle Mine (Box 232C, Folder 1)
      - New York and Cleveland Gas Coal Mine (Box 232C, Folder 2)
      - Pine Run Mine (Box 232C, Folder 3)
      - Risher Mine (Box 232C, Folder 4)
      - Riverville Mine (Box 232C, Folder 5)
      - Rock Run Mine (Box 232C, Folder 6)
      - Rostraver Mine (Box 232C, Folder 7)
      - Six Mile Ferry Mine (Box 232C, Folder 8)
      - Snowhill Mine (Box 232C, Folder 9)
      - Sunnyside Mine (Box 232C, Folder 10)
      - Ten Mile Creek Mine, 1908 (Box 232C, Folder 11)
      - Ten Mile Creek Mine, 1909 (Box 232C, Folder 12)
      - Tremont Mine (Box 232C, Folder 13)
      - Umpire Mine (Box 232C, Folder 14)
      - Victory Mine (Box 232C, Folder 15)
      - Vigilant Mine (Box 232C, Folder 16)
      - Washington Mine (Box 232C, Folder 17)
      - Walton's First Pool Mine (Box 232C, Folder 18)
      - Walton's Second Pool Mine (Box 232C, Folder 19)
      - Yough Mine, Sheet 1 (Box 232C, Folder 20)
      - Yough Mine, Sheet 2 (Box 232C, Folder 21)
      - Brown's Station Landing (Box 232C, Folder 22)
      - City Farm Landing (Box 232C, Folder 23)
      - Clinton Landing (Box 232C, Folder 24)
      - Dunshee Landing (Box 232C, Folder 25)
      - Crump Landing, 1908 (Box 232D, Folder 1)
      - Crump Landing, 1909 (Box 232D, Folder 2)
      - Pittsburg Harbor Landing, unknown (Box 232D, Folder 3)
      - Pittsburg Harbor Landing, 1909 (Box 232D, Folder 4)
      - Lysle Landing, 1908 (Box 232D, Folder 5)
      - Lysle Landing, 1909 (Box 232D, Folder 6)
      - Nimick Landing, Sheet 1, unknown (Box 232D, Folder 7)
      - Nimick Landing, Sheet 2, 1909 (Box 232D, Folder 8)
      - Snyder's Landing (Box 232D, Folder 9)
      - Walton's Landing, unknown (Box 232D, Folder 10)
      - Walton's Landing, 1909 (Box 232D, Folder 11)
      - Watson's Landing, 1908 (Box 232D, Folder 12)
      - Watson's Landing, 1909 (Box 232D, Folder 13)
      - Wood's Landing, unknown (Box 232D, Folder 14)
      - Wood's Landing, 1908 (Box 232D, Folder 15)
      - Wood's Landing, 1909 (Box 232D, Folder 16)
      - Wood's Lower Landing, 1909 (Box 232D, Folder 17)
      - Wood and Horner, 1908 (Box 232D, Folder 18)
      - Wood and Horner, 1909 (Box 232D, Folder 19)
      - Elizabeth Marine Ways (Box 232D, Folder 20)
      - General Office Building Lot (Box 232D, Folder 21)
      - Monongahela Saw and Planing Mill Company Property (Box 232D, Folder 22)
      - Riverton Mill Lot, 1908 (Box 232D, Folder 23)
      - Riverton Mill Lot, 1909 (Box 232D, Folder 24)
      - Walton Docks (Box 232D, Folder 25)
      - Mongah Land Company Lots (Box 232D, Folder 26)
    - Coal mines and coal properties, 2.
      - Index Sheet -- Coal Mines and Coal Properties (Box 232E, Folder 1)
      - Albany Mine (Box 232E, Folder 2)
      - Alice Mine (Box 232E, Folder 3)
      - Aliquippa Mine (Box 232E, Folder 4)
      - Anchor Mine (Box 232E, Folder 5)
      - Apollo Mine (Box 232E, Folder 6)
      - Beaumont Mine (Box 232E, Folder 7)
      - Belle Bridge Mine (Box 232E, Folder 8)
      - Black Diamond Mine (Box 232E, Folder 9)
      - Brown's Fifth Pool Mine (Box 232E, Folder 10)
      - Bunola Mine (Box 232E, Folder 11)
      - Camden Mine (Box 232E, Folder 12)
      - Catsburg Mine (Box 232E, Folder 13)
      - Chamouni Mine (Box 232E, Folder 14)
      - Champion Mine (Box 232E, Folder 15)
      - Cincinnati Mine (Box 232E, Folder 16)
      - Clipper Mine (Box 232E, Folder 17)
      - Coal Bluff Mine (Box 232E, Folder 18)
      - Coal Valley Mine (Box 232E, Folder 19)
      - Crescent and Vigilant Mines, July 15, 1909 (Box 232E, Folder 20)
      - Crescent and Vigilant Mines, October 5, 1909 (Box 232E, Folder 21)
      - Crowthers Mine (Box 232E, Folder 22)
      - Eclipse Mine, July 16, 1909 (Box 232E, Folder 23)
      - Eclipse Mine, September 28, 1909 (Box 232E, Folder 24)
      - Elizabeth Mine, July 16, 1909 (Box 232E, Folder 25)
      - Elizabeth Mine, October 19, 1909 (Box 232F, Folder 1)
      - Fayette City Mine (Box 232F, Folder 2)
      - Fox Mine (Box 232F, Folder 3)
      - Gallatin Mine (Box 232F, Folder 4)
      - Gospel Mine (Box 232F, Folder 5)
      - Guffey Mine (Box 232F, Folder 6)
      - Hays Mine (Box 232F, Folder 7)
      - Hilldale Mine (Box 232F, Folder 8)
      - Holmes Mine (Box 232F, Folder 9)
      - Ivill Mine (Box 232F, Folder 10)
      - Jutte and Maxwell Mines (Box 232F, Folder 11)
      - Knob Mine (Box 232F, Folder 12)
      - Little Redstone Mine (Box 232F, Folder 13)
      - Lovedale Mine (Box 232F, Folder 14)
      - Maple Creek Mine (Box 232F, Folder 15)
      - Mongah and Old Eagle Mines (Box 232F, Folder 16)
      - Mingo Mine (Box 232F, Folder 17)
      - Moorhead Mine (Box 232F, Folder 18)
      - New Eagle Mine (Box 232F, Folder 19)
      - New York and Cleveland Gas Coal Company Mine (Box 232F, Folder 20)
      - Pine Run Mine (Box 232F, Folder 21)
      - Risher Mine (Box 232F, Folder 22)
      - Riverville Mine (Box 232F, Folder 23)
      - Rock Run Mine (Box 232F, Folder 24)
      - Rostraver Mine (Box 232G, Folder 1)
      - Snow Hill Mine (Box 232G, Folder 2)
      - Sunnyside Mine (Box 232G, Folder 3)
      - Ten Mile Mine (Box 232G, Folder 4)
      - Tremont Mine (Box 232G, Folder 5)
      - Umpire Mine (Box 232G, Folder 6)
      - Victory Mine (Box 232G, Folder 7)
      - Walton's First Pool Mine (Box 232G, Folder 8)
      - Walton's Second Pool Mine (Box 232G, Folder 9)
      - Washington Mine (Box 232G, Folder 10)
      - Yough No. 2 Mine (Box 232G, Folder 11)
      - Beck's Run Mine (Box 232G, Folder 12)
      - Six Mile Ferry Mine (Box 232G, Folder 13)
      - Albany, Alice, Anchor, Chamouni, Snow Hill and Washington Mines (Box 232G, Folder 14)
      - Aliquippa, Camden, Risher and Six Mile Ferry Mines (Box 232G, Folder 15)
      - Apollo and Fayette City Mines (Box 232G, Folder 16)
      - Black Diamond, Hays, Ivill, Moorhead and Victory Mines (Box 232G, Folder 17)
      - Brown's Fifth Pool and Fox Mines (Box 232G, Folder 18)
      - Bunola, Mongah and Old Eagle Mines (Box 232G, Folder 19)
      - Coal Valley, Pine Run and Rock Run Mines (Box 232G, Folder 20)
      - Gallatin and Sunnyside Mines (Box 232G, Folder 21)
      - Holmes, Mingo and New Eagle Mines (Box 232G, Folder 22)
      - Lovedale and Yough No. 2 Mines (Box 232G, Folder 23)
      - Walton's Second Pool and Hilldale Mines (Box 232G, Folder 24)
  - 2008 Outstanding Reclamation Award - Coal presented to CONSOL Energy Inc. for their Illinois Surface Operations by the National Association of State Land Reclamationists (Box 233, Folder 1)
  - Coal Refuse Impoundment North Award presented by the West Virginia Coal Association to Island Creek Coal Company, Beaver Creek Slurry Impoundment (Box 233, Folder 2)
  - 2006 Reclamation Award presented by the West Virginia Coal Association to Laurel Run Mining Company, Potomac Mine, East Complex (Box 233, Folder 3)
  - Excellence in Mining Reclamation Certificate awarded to Island Creek Coal Company for "Best Completed Deep Mine" by Virginia Mining Association (Box 233, Folder 4)
  - 2003 National Award for Reclamation from National Mining Association (Box 233, Folder 5)
  - 2004 Excellence in Coal Surface Mining and Reclamation National Award (Box 233, Folder 6)
- Publications, 1915-2010; XIX.
  This series contains monographs, serials, articles, newsclippings, brochures, etc. about CONSOL Energy and other activities related to coal mining.
  - Monographs Published by CONSOL, 1.
    - History of the Consolidated Coal Company, 1864-1934 / compiled by Charles E. Beachley (Box 234, Folder 1)
    - CONSOL Coals, ca. 1951 (Box 234, Folder 2)
    - Coal Pipeline / by V. D. Hanson and T. J. Regan, 1958 (Box 234, Folder 3)
    - CONSOL: a brief review of the U. S. bituminous coal industry, Consolidation Coal Company, its divisions, its subsidiaries and associated companies, 1961 (Box 234, Folder 4)
    - CONSOL Centennial Issue, reprinted from Coal Age, October 1964 (Box 234, Folder 5)
    - The CONSOL Story, 1966 (Box 234, Folder 6)
    - Energy in motion for men in motion, this is CONSOL, ca. 1967 (Box 234, Folder 7)
    - Kellogg Dock / Consolidation Coal Company, Truax-Traer Division, ca. 1967 (Box 234, Folder 8)
    - CONSOL ... the energy company for men on the move, 1969 (Box 234, Folder 9)
    - CONSOL, 1974 (Box 234, Folder 10)
    - Consolidation Coal 27th Annual Central Division Safety Day, 1974 (Box 234, Folder 11)
    - CONSOL, 1975 (Box 234, Folder 12)
    - Pittsburgh Division Annual Visitation, 1975 (Box 234, Folder 13)
    - CONSOL, 1977 (Box 234, Folder 14)
    - CONSOL Pittsburgh General Office Handbook, 1977 (Box 234, Folder 15)
    - Consolidation Coal 30th Annual Underground Picnic, 1977 (Box 234, Folder 16)
    - Consolidation Coal Company Corporate Headquarters Information Guide, 1978 (Box 234, Folder 17)
    - The CX Ranch Conference Center, Big Horn County, Montana, ca. 1980 (Box 234, Folder 18)
    - Cost/Benefit Analysis of Deep Mine Federal Safety Legislation and Enforcement, 1980 (Box 234, Folder 19)
    - CONSOL: a world leader in the production, processing, transportation and marketing of coal, 1981 (Box 234, Folder 20)
    - DuPont/CONOCO Presentation, 1981 (Box 234, Folder 21)
    - Consolidation Coal Company Midwest Region Executive Tour, June 20-21, 1984 (Box 234, Folder 22)
    - Consolidation Coal Company Eastern Region Executive Visit, October 9-10, 1984 (Box 234, Folder 23)
    - The New Face of Coal: CONSOL, ca. 1985 (Box 234, Folder 24)
    - CONSOL, 1986 (Box 234, Folder 25)
    - CONSOL Energy Corporate Headquarters, 2007 (Box 234, Folder 26)
  - Serials Published by CONSOL, 2.
    - Sample newsletters from various mines in CONSOL's Eastern Region (Box 234, Folder 27)
    - Consolidation Coal Company annual reports, 1943-1944 (Box 234, Folder 28)
      See Also
      Pittsburgh Coal Company annual reports to stockholders, 1900-1940; filed in Box 226, Folders 6-10.
    - Pittsburgh Consolidation Coal Company annual reports, 1945 (Box 234, Folder 29)
      - Consolidation Coal Company Annual Report, 1943
      - Consolidation Coal Company Annual Report, 1944
    - CONSOL Highlights, 1992, 1995-1997 (Box 234, Folder 30)
    - CONSOL Energy annual report, 2002 (Box 234, Folder 31)
    - The CONSOL Dealer, 1946 (Box 234, Folder 32)
    - The CONSOL Dealer, 1947 (Box 234, Folder 33)
    - The CONSOL Dealer, 1949 (Box 234, Folder 34)
    - The CONSOL Dealer, 1950 (Box 234, Folder 35)
    - The CONSOL Dealer, 1951 (Box 234, Folder 36)
    - CONSOL News
      Issues of CONSOL News and CONSOL Energy News are online in Historic Pittsburgh. Only copies of CONSOL News are in the collection; issues of CONSOL Energy News were borrowed from CONSOL Energy, Inc. for scanning purposes.
      - CONSOL News, 1962-1965 (Box 235, Folder 1)
      - CONSOL News, 1966-1969 (Box 235, Folder 2)
      - CONSOL News, 1970-1971 (Box 235, Folder 3)
      - CONSOL News, 1979-1980 (Box 235A, Folder 1)
      - CONSOL News, 1981-1982 (Box 235A, Folder 2)
      - CONSOL News, 1983-1985 (Box 235A, Folder 3)
      - CONSOL News, 1986-1989 (Box 235A, Folder 4)
      - CONSOL News, 1990-1993 (Box 235A, Folder 5)
      - CONSOL News, 1994-1999 (Box 235A, Folder 6)
  - Publications by Other Coal Companies, 3.
    - Continental Oil Company annual report, 1966 (Box 235, Folder 4)
    - CONOCO: the first one hundred years, 1975 (Box 235, Folder 5)
    - Guyan Eagle Coal: a photographic story of Guyan Eagle Coal Company and its subsidiary, Elk Creek Coal Company / by Harry N. Taylor, ca. 1963 (Box 235, Folder 6)
    - Hanna Coal Company, ca. 1956 (Box 235, Folder 7)
    - Mighty sun give thy light to us, let it guide us, let it aid us / Hanna Coal Company, ca. 1971 (Box 235, Folder 8)
    - Hanna Coal News, Volumes 29-30, 1961-1962 (Box 235, Folder 9)
    - "Island Creek": a career company dedicated to coal! Saga in bituminous! / Raymond E. Salvati, 1957 (Box 235, Folder 10)
    - Island Creek Precisoneered Coal: the story of a career company dedicated to coal, ca. 1965 (Box 235, Folder 11)
    - Island Creek, ca. 1990 (Box 235, Folder 12)
    - The Luscar Story / compiled by N. Allen Maydonik, 1985 (Box 235, Folder 13)
    - A History of Marion Power Shovel's First 100 Years, 1884-1984 / by Keith Haddock, 1994 (Box 235, Folder 14)
    - Occidental Petroleum Company Corporate Policies: Finance, Volume 1, 1992 (Box 235, Folder 15)
    - 100 Years of Excellence: a history of the Pittsburg & Midway Coal Mining Co., 1885-1985 (Box 235, Folder 16)
    - The Story of Pocahontas, 1863-1915: a good coal (Box 235, Folder 17)
    - American Institute of Mining and Metallurgical Engineers Pocahontas Tour: October 9, 1924 (Box 235, Folder 18)
    - Drainage Tunnel of Pocahontas Fuel Company Incorporated, 1936 (Box 235, Folder 19)
    - Gates Engineering Company Report on Quarto Mining Company's Powhatan No. 7 Mine, 1977 (Box 235, Folder 20)
    - Quarto Mining Company Plan for Approval to Construct Two Ventilation Shafts [in] Powhatan No. 4 Mine, 1987 (Box 235, Folder 21)
    - The Quarto Mining Project / prepared by Quarto Mining Company, 1973 (Box 235, Folder 22)
    - The Quarto Mining Project, Supplement A / prepared by Quarto Mining Company, 1977 (Box 235, Folder 23)
    - Rochester & Pittsburgh Coal Company: the first one hundred years / Eileen Mountjoy Cooper, 1982 (Box 235, Folder 24)
    - History of Truax-Traer Coal Company, ca. 1952 (Box 235, Folder 25)
  - Publications Related to Coal Mines and Mining, 4.
    - Coal mining handbook, 3rd ed. / International Correspondence Schools, 1928 (Box 236, Folder 1)
    - Steam engineer's handbook, 1st ed. / International Correspondence Schools, 1928 (Box 236, Folder 2)
    - Coradi planimeters / by G. Coradi, 1917 (Box 236, Folder 3)
    - Catalogue and price list of B. K. Elliott Co., manufacturers and importers of drawing materials and surveying instruments, 7th ed., 1955 (Box 236, Folder 4)
    - Treatise on surveying, 14th ed. / by John Gunmere, 1843 (Box 236, Folder 5)
    - Accounting manual for the Consolidation Coal Company, effective January 1, 1929, with Supplement no. 3, effective September 1, 1932 (Box 236, Folder 6)
    - Keystone coal mining catalog, 1927 (Box 236, Folder 7)
    - Keystone coal buyers manual, including directory of mines, 1940 (Box 236, Folder 8)
    - Basic surveying / Pittsburgh Coal Company Division, Consolidation Coal Company, October 1970 (Box 236, Folder 9)
    - Coal and metal miners' pocketbook of principles, rules, formulas and tables, 7th ed., (PHOTOCOPY), 1902 (Box 236, Folder 10)
    - The Human Side, Nos. 100-103, 117, 128-131, 133-150, 1950-1952 (Box 236, Folder 11)
    - The Human Side, Nos. 151-178, 1952-1955 (Box 236, Folder 12)
    - The Human Side, Nos. 183-235 (odd numbers only), 1955-1957 (Box 236, Folder 13)
    - Concerning coal: an anthology / edited by Magdalen Mayer, Mara Lou Hawse, Paul J. Maloney, 1997 (Box 236, Folder 14)
    - Monongah disaster, 50 anniversary year, 1907-1957, Catholic Churches of Monongah, West Virginia, St. Stanislaus Church, Our Lady of Pompeii Church / Rev. Everett F. Briggs (Box 236, Folder 15)
    - What is coal? / by Reinhardt Thiessen, 1947 (Box 236, Folder 16)
    - Study of coal mining and related resources in southern West Virginia, 1993 (Box 236, Folder 17)
    - Underground coal mining in western Maryland, 1876-1977: a reference guide / by Vagel Charles Keller, Jr.; maps by Jaron Hawkins, 2008 (Box 236, Folder 18)
    - Black gold: a tribute to coal miners, 2007 (Box 236, Folder 19)
    - Coal: a contemporary energy story / by Kristin Lindbergh and Barry Provorse, 1977 (Box 237, Folder 1)
    - King Coal: a pictorial heritage of West Virginia coal mining / by Stan Cohen, 1984 (Box 237, Folder 2)
    - Story of mine drainage: a problem for West Virginia / West Virginia Coal Association, ca. 1956 (Box 237, Folder 3)
    - Historical mining disasters / by Jane DeMarchi, ca. 1997 (Box 237, Folder 4)
    - Coal mines on the Chesapeake and Ohio Railway, 1966 (Box 237, Folder 5)
    - Blue book of Kentucky coal / Kentucky Energy Cabinet, 1985 (Box 237, Folder 6)
    - Coal river terminals serving Kentucky / Kentucky Energy Cabinet, 1985 (Box 237, Folder 7)
    - American coal miner: a report on community and living conditions in the coalfields / President's Commission on Coal, 1980 (Box 237, Folder 8)
    - Problems of the transportation of solids by pipeline / C. L. Coldren, 1963 (Box 237, Folder 9)
    - Coal pipelines: a handbook of facts on a new industry / prepared by Texas Eastern Transmission Corporation and Consolidation Coal Company, ca. 1962 (Box 237, Folder 10)
    - History of Greene County coal mining / G. Wayne Smith, 1995 (Box 237, Folder 11)
    - Work, safety, and life style among southern Appalachian coal miners: a survey of the men of Standard Mines / by Ronald Althouse, 1974 (Box 237, Folder 12)
    - Coal industry in America: a bibliography and guide to studies, 2nd ed. / Robert F. Munn, 1977 (Box 237, Folder 13)
    - Elements of practical coal mining / edited by Samuel M. Cassidy, 1973 (Box 237, Folder 14)
    - Coal, energy for the next decade and beyond: the National Coal Association forecast for U.S. coal, 1900-2000 (Box 237, Folder 15)
    - History of the coal-mining industry in Ohio / by Douglas L. Crowell, 1995 (Box 237, Folder 16)
    - All about oil: its origin, production and use: an Imperial Oil teaching aid, ca. 1975 (Box 237, Folder 17)
    - Supply and demand for United States coking coals and metallurgical coke / by Eugene T. Sheridan, 1976 (Box 237, Folder 18)
    - Final report on major explosion and fire disaster No. 9 mine, Jamison Coal and Coke Company, Farmington, Marion County, West Virginia, November 13, 1954 / by W. R. Park, ca. 1956 (Box 237, Folder 19)
    - Coal and research / National Coal Association and its affiliate Bituminous Coal Research, 1975 (Box 237, Folder 20)
    - Coal in today's world / Education Division, National Coal Association, 1974 (Box 237, Folder 21)
    - Pennsylvania coal in crisis: facts and opinions / Keystone Bituminous Coal Association, ca. 1986 (Box 237, Folder 22)
    - Electricity supply in Ireland: the history of the ESB / Maurice Manning and Moore McDowell, 1984 (Box 237, Folder 23)
    - Coal: reprinted from The World Book Encyclopedia, 1975 (Box 237, Folder 24)
    - Coal data book / President's Commission on Coal, 1980 (Box 237, Folder 25)
    - Report of the United States Coal Mining Delegation to the USSR, May 30-June 16, 1970 (Box 237, Folder 26)
    - 24 hours, 25 years EMO = 24 uur, 25 jaar EMO, 1998 (Box 237, Folder 27)
    - History of the development of self-contained breathing apparatus used in mine rescue operations, ca. 2008 (Box 237, Folder 28)
    - Compleat collier, or, The whole art of sinking, getting and working, coal mines, &c.: as is now used in the northern part, especially about Sunderland and New-Castle (photocopy of 1935 facsimile reprint of 1708 edition) (Box 237, Folder 29)
    - Coal, February, April-May, 1988 (Box 237, Folder 30)
    - Pittsburgh Coal Company mine accident statistics, 1927-1938 (Box 238, Folder 1)
    - Amount of bonus paid to superintendents, 1934-1937 (Box 238, Folder 2)
    - Workmen's compensation expenses and reserves, 1942-1946 (Box 238, Folder 3)
    - Rand McNally business traveler's road atlas and guide to major cities, 1985 (Box 238, Folder 4)
    - Coal is what we make it: special issue of Fortune, March 1947 (Box 238, Folder 5)
    - Britain's Railways: special issue of Fortune, April 1947 (Box 238, Folder 6)
  - Articles, Newsletters, Clippings, Brochures, etc., 5.
    - CONSOL memorabilia and fact sheets (Box 239, Folder 1)
    - Advertising and publicity (Box 239, Folder 2)
    - P. C. C. News, Vol. 6, No. 6, September 1945 (Box 239, Folder 3)
    - Hanna Coal News, August 1960 (Box 239, Folder 4)
    - CONSOL Centennial Issue, 1864-1964: reprinted from Coal Age, October 1964 (Box 239, Folder 5)
    - Island Creek Coal Company: special issue of Coal Age, October 1965 (Box 239, Folder 6)
    - Profile of Consolidation Coal Company: special issue of Coal Age, October 1972 (Box 239, Folder 7)
    - Ohio Mining and Reclamation Newsletter, February 1985 (Box 239, Folder 8)
    - Corporate Profile, Consolidation Coal: reprinted from Coal, October 1988 (Box 239, Folder 9)
    - CONSOL, 125 years, 1864-1989: special supplement to CoalTrans International (Box 239, Folder 10)
    - Biographical articles (Box 239, Folder 11)
    - News articles, 1947 (Box 239, Folder 12)
    - News articles on new "Coal into Gas" plant, 1947-1948 (Box 239, Folder 13)
    - News articles, 1948 (Box 239, Folder 14)
    - News articles, 1949 (Box 239, Folder 15)
    - News articles, 1957-1959 (Box 239, Folder 18)
    - News articles, 1950-1954 (Box 239, Folder 16)
    - News articles, 1955-1956 (Box 239, Folder 17)
    - News articles, 1960-1967 (Box 239, Folder 19)
    - News articles on Mountaineer No. 9 Mine disaster, 1968-1969 (Box 239, Folder 20)
    - News articles, 1969-1979 (Box 239, Folder 21)
    - News articles, 1980-1989 (Box 239, Folder 22)
    - News articles, 1990-1999 (Box 239, Folder 23)
    - News articles on the sale of the Rochester and Pittsburgh Coal Company, 1997 (Box 239, Folder 24)
    - News articles, 2000-2010 (Box 239, Folder 25)
- Quecreek Mine Accident Investigation, 1900-2004; XX.
  Arrangement
  Series materials are further divided into 13 topical subseries and range in date from 1900 to 2004.